CARLOS EDUARDO ESTRADA SUÁREZ

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

+573502606243 • carlosestrada94@outlook.com • https://cees.dev/ • Bogotá, Colombia

Summary

As a frontend developer, I have a deep passion for online learning and programming. My focus is on using JavaScript to solve problems in the best possible way, with a particular emphasis on clean and readable code. My experience and skills lie in React.js and its APIs such as Hooks, and libraries like Redux, Zustand and Tanstack libraries including Tanstack Query and Tanstack Table. Additionally, I have a strong interest in UI prototyping and design using Figma.

Skills

Programming languages: JavaScript \cdot TypeScript \cdot Python

Libraries and frameworks: React.js · Next.js · React-Redux · Zustand · Tailwind CSS · JQuery

Software: Visual Studio Code · Webstorm · Figma

Platforms: AWS · AWS Lambda · AWS API Gateway · AWS S3

Experience

CreateMe Technologies S.A.S.

Remote

Associate Frontend Engineer (full-time)

10/2022 - Ongoing

- Developing and implementing 2D and 3D product customization platforms for online retail
- Improved the performance of Ralph Lauren's 2D product customization platform by approximately 30%, resulting in a smoother and faster user experience for customers

Fintegra S.A.S. Bogotá, Colombia

Frontend Developer (full-time)

09/2021 - 09/2022

- · Redesigned the landing page and application dashboard using Figma, resulting in a more user-friendly and visually appealing design
- Utilized React.js and Tailwind CSS to implement the new designs and ensure a responsive and efficient user experience
- Modernized the app build tooling by implementing Vite, resulting in faster build times and improved productivity
- Optimized the data fetching and server state management using Tanstack Query

Webcat Remote

Software QA Developer (contractor)

05/2021 - 08/2021

- · Conducted manual testing of the Webcat app builder platform to evaluate functionality and user experience
- Developed reusable components, such as forms, using Vue.js for Webcat platform users
- Translated Webcat documentation from Spanish to English, ensuring that users from different regions could access and understand the platform's features and functionalities
- Provided customer support to Webcat platform users, resolving technical issues and answering queries in a timely manner

Solteco S.A.S. Remote

Node.js Developer (contractor)

03/2021 - 08/2021

- Developed a Node.js web socket server that communicates with the Emotiv Cortex API to integrate a video game created in Unity
- This video game is part of a research project led by Universidad El Bosque and Enel Codensa

Education

Concordia University

Montréal, QC, Canada

Bachelor's degree, Computer engineering (Incomplete)

09/2018 - 09/2019

Universidad de Los Andes

Bachelor's degree, Economics

Bogotá, Colombia
01/2013 - 01/2018

Centre Linguistique Du College De Jonquière

French

01/2012 - 06/2012

Jonquière, QC, Canada

Liceo Cervantes Norte

Bogotá, Colombia

Primary and secondary education

01/1999 - 12/2011

Languages

Spanish Native •••• English Proficient ••••

French Intermediate • • • •